Guide to the Walter L. Pforzheimer Collection of Frank Richard Stockton
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Walter L. Pforzheimer collection of Frank Richard Stockton
1829-1993
1880-1940
YCAL MSS 560
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12.71
(26 boxes) + 19 broadside, 3 art
The Walter L. Pforzheimer Collection of Frank Richard Stockton contains correspondence, writings, photographs, artifacts, and other personal papers of Stockton and his family; drawings by illustrators of Stockton's works; writings about Stockton and adaptations of his works by others; and correspondence, notes, and related materials created by Pforzheimer in the course of his research and collecting. Correspondence includes autograph letters, signed, to and from Stockton, many with literary correspondents. Writings by Stockton include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts and fair copies, tear sheets from magazines, publisher contracts, advertisements, and scrapbooks of reviews. Also present are autograph manuscript diaries, accounts, notes, and juvenile writings by Stockton. Pen-and-ink and watercolor drawings, many with publisher's markings, include works by A. B. Frost, Charles Dana Gibson, Frederick Richardson, Frederic Dorr Steele, and other artists. Materials relating to the Stockton family include correspondence, scrapbooks, and photographs. Materials relating to Pforzheimer's research and collecting include vendor correspondence and receipts, notes, and card catalogs.
Pforzheimer, Walter L. (Walter Lionel), 1914-2003
Stockton, Frank R., 1834-1902
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Walter L. Pforzheimer (Yale 1935, Yale 1938L), 1997 and 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
39-42 (Art): Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
Walter L. Pforzheimer Papers (GEN MSS 817)
Walter L. Pforzheimer Collection of Historical Manuscripts (GEN MSS 838)
Frank Richard Stockton (1834-1902)
Frank Richard Stockton, American author and humorist. Stockton worked as a wood engraver before beginning his literary career. During 1860-1902, he published novels, short stories, short story collections, and articles, and became a popular author of stories for children. His works include stories Ting-a-ling Tales (1882), The Floating Prince, and Other Fairy Tales (1881), and The Lady, or the Tiger? (1882), and novels Rudder Grange (1879), Rudder Grangers Abroad (1891), Pomona's Travels (1894), The Casting Away of Mrs. Lecks and Mrs. Aleshine (1886), and The Dusantes (1888). Stockton served as an editor of Hearth and Home, 1868-1874, and Saint Nicholas Magazine, 1874-878. He married Marian Edwards Tuttle in 1860.
Sources:
Griffin, Martin Ignatius Joseph. Frank R. Stockton: A Critical Biography (Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press, 1939).
Golemba, Henry L. Frank R. Stockton (Boston: Twayne Publishers, 1981).
Walter L. Pforzheimer (1914-2003)
Walter L. Pforzheimer, lawyer, intelligence officer, and book collector. Pforzheimer was born in Port Chester, New York, in 1914, and graduated from Yale College (1935) and Yale Law School (1938). Pforzheimer began his intelligence career in the United States Army, 1942-1945, in the Office of Strategic Services and as an Army Air Force intelligence officer. He was one of the founders of the Central Intelligence Agency in 1946, and as a CIA legislative counsel and liaison to Congress assisted in drafting the 1947 National Security Act. In 1956, he founded the CIA's Historical Intelligence Collection, which he curated until his retirement in 1974. In retirement, he continued to work for the CIA and taught at the Defense Intelligence College. Pforzheimer died in Washington, D.C., in 2003.
Pforzheimer came from a family of book collectors: his father, also named Walter Pforzheimer (1883-1955), collected French armorial bindings and assembled a virtually complete collection of Molière; his uncle Carl H. Pforzheimer (1879-1957) collected Percy Bysshe Shelley and his circle. Pforzheimer inherited and augmented his father's collections, and assembled his own collection of American novelist Frank Richard Stockton. In addition to curating the CIA's Historical Intelligence Collection, Pforzheimer built a personal collection of books and manuscripts documenting the history of military intelligence. Elected to the Yale Library Associates board of trustees in 1936, Pforzheimer was a life-long trustee and donor to the Yale Libraries. He donated his book and manuscript collections of Molière, French armorial bindings, Frank Richard Stockton, and military intelligence to the Beinecke Library in 2001.
Sources:
Peake, Hayden B. "Walter Pforzheimer -- Lawyer, Intelligence Officer, Bibliophile." In: In the Name of Intelligence: Essays in Honor of Walter Pforzheimer (Washington: NIBC Press, c1994).
"Walter L. Pforzheimer, CIA's First Curator, Dies at 88." Washington Post (2003 February 12).
Scope and Contents
The Walter L. Pforzheimer Collection of Frank Richard Stockton contains correspondence, writings, photographs, artifacts, and other personal papers of Stockton and his family; drawings by illustrators of Stockton's works; writings about Stockton and adaptations of his works by others; and correspondence, notes, and related materials created by Pforzheimer in the course of his research and collecting. Correspondence includes autograph letters, signed, to and from Stockton, many with literary correspondents. Writings by Stockton include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts and fair copies, tear sheets from magazines, publisher contracts, advertisements, and scrapbooks of reviews. Also present are autograph manuscript diaries, accounts, notes, and juvenile writings by Stockton. Pen-and-ink and watercolor drawings, many with publisher's markings, include works by A. B. Frost, Charles Dana Gibson, Frederick Richardson, Frederic Dorr Steele, and other artists. Materials relating to the Stockton family include correspondence, scrapbooks, and photographs. Materials relating to Pforzheimer's research and collecting include vendor correspondence and receipts, notes, and card catalogs.
Research strengths include Frank Richard Stockton's life and writings; reception of his works; publishers, editors, and illustrators associated with Stockton; the Stockton family; nineteenth-century American magazines and children's literature; and book and manuscript collecting and the formation of Pforzheimer's collection.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: November 2000 Acquisition, November 2000 Acquisition Addition, and January 1997 Acquisition Addition.
Hearth and home (New York, N.Y.); St. Nicholas (New York, N.Y.); American literature -- 19th century; Artists -- United States; Authors, American -- 19th century -- Archives; Authors and artists -- United States; Authors and publishers -- United States; Book collecting -- United States; Book collectors -- United States; Children's literature -- Illustrations; Children's literature, American; Children's periodicals, American; Humorists, American -- 19th century; Illustration of books -- 19th century; Illustrators -- United States; Manuscripts -- Collectors and collecting -- United States; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Contracts -- United States -- 19th century; Diaries -- United States -- 19th century; Drawings (visual works) -- United States -- 19th century; Oil paintings (visual works) -- United States -- 19th century; Photograph albums -- United States -- 19th century; Photographs -- United States -- 19th century; Scrapbooks -- United States -- 19th century; Watercolors (paintings) -- United States -- 19th century; Wood blocks (printing blocks) -- United States -- 19th century; Artists -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 19th century; Book collectors -- United States -- 20th Century; Humorists -- United States -- 20th Century; Illustrators -- United States -- 20th Century; Frost, A. B. (Arthur Burdett), 1851-1928; Gibson, Charles Dana, 1867-1944; Pforzheimer, Walter L. (Walter Lionel), 1914-2003; Richardson, Frederick, 1862-1937; Steele, Frederic Dorr, 1873-1944; Stockton, Frank R., 1834-1902; Stockton, Marian E. (Marian Edwards), -1906; Stockton family
- November 2000 Acquisition, 1829-1965; 11.88; (22 boxes) + 17 broadside folders, 2 object storage items, 1 framed art item
  Arrangement
  Folders are unarranged, and folder contents have not been verified.
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this grouping were removed from the Walter L. Pforzheimer Papers in 2003. Personal names and titles of works have not been standardized. Most Stockton autograph letters and manuscripts and original drawings by illustrators are identified in folder titles; some folder titles consisting of names or topical subjects contain additional similar materials. Some folders identified by vendor names include both vendor correspondence and Stockton manuscripts purchased by Pforzheimer. A small amount of materials appear to be unrelated to Stockton, reflecting an incomplete division with the Pforzheimer Papers. These include Pforzheimer family photographs and papers of other authors collected by Pforzheimer.
  - Papers Relating to Frank Richard Stockton
    - Photograph, undated (Box 1)
    - Last will and testament, Mary Ann Edward Stockton, 1905? (Box 1)
    - "The Cloverfields Carriage," Century Magazine, 1886 Jan (Box 1)
    - "A Tale of Negative Gravity," Century Magazine, 1884 Nov (Box 1)
    - "The Philosophy of Relative Existences," Century Magazine, 1892 Aug (Box 1)
    - "Captain Eli's Best Ear," Century Magazine, 1895 Dec (Box 1)
    - "The Water-Devil," Scribner's Magazine, 1891 Jan-Feb (Box 1)
    - "Euphemia Among the Pelicans," Century Magazine, 1882 Feb (Box 1)
    - "The Rudder Grangers in England," Century Magazine, 1883 Jan (Box 1)
    - Photograph, Sterling Memorial Library, Yale University, undated (Box 1)
    - Family photographs, undated (Box 1)
    - "The Hermit's Stocking: A Merry Christmas Story," bound with a sketch, undated (Box 1)
    - "To Thomas Mann," Dorothy Thompson
    - Photostat articles
    - Signed letter to Editor of the Independent, undated (Box 1)
    - Signed letter to M. Land Simons, 1873 Jun 16 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified letters, [circa 1875-1938]; 5 (Box 1)
    - Signed letter from John Whittier to Mrs. Dodge, 1880 (Box 2)
    - Materials related to "The Squirrel Inn," including several signed letters and photographs, 1893-1900 (Box 2)
    - Contracts, 1891-1903 (Box 2)
    - "The Lady or the Tiger," copy from NBC, 1941 Oct 29 (Box 2)
    - "Stocktoniana #2", 1936 (Box 2)
    - Letters regarding "The Bicycle of Cathay," FRS to Gilder, 1899 Aug 24 (Box 2)
    - Letters regarding "The Merry Christmas," FRS to Carey/RU Johnson of Century, 1888-1889 (Box 2)
    - Letters regarding "The Captain's Toll Gate" 1900-1903 (Box 2)
    - Letters FRS, bibliographical material, 1897 Aug 7 (Box 2)
    - Letters regarding FRS's death, 1902 (Box 2)
    - On International Copyright laws, undated (Box 2)
    - FRS Bibliographical letters and personal letters, 1889-1895 (Box 2)
    - Marian E. Stockton, undated (Box 2)
    - "The Mentor", 1913 Jun 30 (Box 2)
    - "The Literary News," "The Captain's Toll Gate," a view of Stockton's study, 1903 Jul (Box 2)
    - "Great Thoughts", 1891 Dec 26 (Box 2)
    - Letters to Frederic W. Speirs, signed, 1901 (Box 2)
    - Letters from Marian Stockton Cantrell, 1936 (Box 2)
    - "The Dusantes," "A Tale of Negative Gravity," from a magazine, clipping, 1884 Nov (Box 2)
    - "The Dusantes," Century Magazine, clipping, 1887-1888 (Box 2)
    - "The Reversible Landscape," Century Magazine, clipping, 1884 (Box 2)
    - "The Romance of a Mule-Car," Century Magazine, clipping, 1897 (Box 2)
    - "The Remarkable Wreck of the Thomas Hyke," Century Magazine, clipping, 1884 (Box 2)
    - "Our Story," Century Magazine, 1883 (Box 2)
    - "On the Training of Parents," Century Magazine, clipping, 1884 (Box 2)
    - "The Merry Chanter," Century Magazine, clipping, 1889-1890 (Box 3)
    - "The Magic Egg," Century Magazine, clipping, 1894 (Box 3)
    - "The Squirrel Inn," Century Magazine, clipping, 1891 (Box 3)
    - Library of the World's Best Literature: The Casting Away Leaves, [circa 1890-1936] (Box 3)
    - "The Christmas Shadrock," Century Magazine, clipping, 1891 (Box 3)
    - "Pomona's Daughter," Century Magazine, 1883-1885 (Box 3)
    - "A Borrowed Month," Century Magazine, clipping, 1886 (Box 3)
    - Original magazine parts, 1887-1894 (Box 3)
    - "The Lady or the Tiger?" Century Magazine, clipping, 1882 (Box 3)
    - "The Vizier of the Two-Horned Alexander" Century Magazine, clipping, 1898 (Box 3)
    - "His Wife's Deceased Sister," Century Magazine, clipping, 1884 (Box 3)
    - "A Story of Seven Devils," Century Magazine, clipping, 1885 (Box 3)
    - Poems, [circa 1850-1870] (Box 3)
    - Cartoon, "The Lady or the Tiger?" photostat, undated (Box 3)
    - Letters, FRS regarding "The Story of Viteau", 1880 Oct 30 (Box 3)
    - "The Lady or the Tiger?" photostat of original manuscript, undated (Box 3)
    - Claymont, photographs, undated (Box 3)
    - "The Lady or the Tiger?" Herford drawings, photostats, undated (Box 3)
    - "Our Story," "The Spectral Mortgage," "Rudder Grangers in England," Century Magazine, clipping, 1883 (Box 3)
    - Martin Griffin, Biography of FRS, 1939 (Box 3)
    - Portraits, undated (Box 3)
    - The Holt, Stockton's home, undated (Box 3)
    - Claymont, real estate advertisement, other pictures, undated (Box 3)
    - Autographs, undated (Box 3)
    - A memorial sketch by Mrs. Stockton, recollections by George Cary Eggleston, 1903 (Box 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 3)
    - Sterling Memorial Library exhibition cards and information related to Stockton materials, undated (Box 4)
    - "Pomona of Rudder Grange," unpublished typescript play, undated (Box 4)
    - "Prince Hassak's March," public reading, undated (Box 4)
    - Stockton estate sale catalogues, 1932 (Box 4)
    - "The Spirit of Genius," by FRS, autograph manuscript, 1851 (Box 4)
    - Deed for Cedar Hall Female Seminary, 1858 (Box 4)
    - "The Knife that Killed Po Haney," copyright paper, 1891 (Box 4)
    - Unidentified letters, 1885 (Box 4)
    - Phelps on Stockton, undated (Box 4)
    - Dictionary of American Biography: article on Stockton, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Claymont: deed of sale, 1899 (Box 4)
    - "Amos Kilbright and Other Stories," contract, 1888 (Box 4)
    - "Amos Kilbright," copyright reservation, 1888 (Box 4)
    - "Ardis Claverden," contract, 1890 (Box 4)
    - Letters regarding "Associate Hermits", 1897 (Box 4)
    - Unidentified Stockton autographs, undated (Box 4)
    - Ancient Order of Bandits, 1848 (Box 4)
    - Letters patent, undated (Box 4)
    - Cantrell, Mrs. George E., 1936-1939 (Box 5)
    - Sheldon, Helene Stockton, 1935 (Box 5)
    - Letters to Horace E. Scudder, 1869-1901 (Box 5)
    - "The House of Martha," contracts, 1890 (Box 5)
    - "John Gather's Garden," contracts, 1902 (Box 5)
    - "A Jolly Fellowship," contract, 1880 (Box 5)
    - "A Real Union," original manuscript, undated (Box 5)
    - Unidentified letters, 1896-1901; 2 (Box 5)
    - Speech on centenary of Stockton's birth by Professor William Lyon Phelps, 1934 (Box 5)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 5)
    - "Horse Sense and Horse Affections," manuscript (Box 5)
    - "The House of Ransom," correspondence, 1884 (Box 5)
    - "Old Pipes and the Dryad," original manuscript, translation in French, undated (Box 5)
    - "Personal Affairs," correspondence, 1850 (Box 5)
    - "The Story of a Mongol Boy," original manuscript (Box 5)
    - "A Story of Seven Devils," correspondence, undated (Box 5)
    - "The Story Spoiler," original manuscript, undated (Box 5)
    - "A Story Teller's Pack," contracts, 1897 (Box 5)
    - "Tales Out of School," contracts, circa 1876 (Box 5)
    - "Ting-A-Ling," contract and copyright, 1869-1882 (Box 5)
    - "The Transferred Ghost," original play manuscript (Box 5)
    - "The Vizier of the Two-Horned Alexander," contracts, 1899 (Box 5)
    - "The Watchmaker's Wife," contracts, 1893 (Box 5)
    - "A Way out of the Philippine Embarrassment," original manuscript, undated (Box 5)
    - "The Stories of the Three Burglars," contracts, 1889 (Box 5)
    - "A Bicycle of Cathay," contract, 1899 (Box 5)
    - Letter regarding Chicago World's Fair, 1893 (Box 5)
    - De Camp, Etta, article on her spiritualism and Stockton, The North American Mag. Section, Philadelphia Jun 2, 1912 (Box 5)
    - Letter to Mrs. Sol Eytinge, 1876 (Box 6)
    - Letter on the flag, New York Herald, Jul 3, 1898 (Box 6)
    - "The Hundredth Man," contracts, 1887 (Box 6)
    - Letters regarding "The Hundredth Man", 1886 (Box 6)
    - Elinor Wylie, "Rondeau: A Windy Day", undated (Box 6)
    - "The Spirit of Washington", undated (Box 6)
    - "The Spirit of Washington," copyright, 1895 (Box 6)
    - Manasquian newspaper, 1902 (Box 6)
    - "The Squirrel Inn," play program, 1893 (Box 6)
    - "The Squirrel Inn," play letter, 1893 (Box 6)
    - "A Northern Voice for the Dissolution of the Unions," pamphlet, 1860 (Box 6)
    - Letters regarding "Buccaneers and Pirates of our Coast", 1897 (Box 6)
    - "Buccaneers and Pirates of our Coast," contract, 1897 (Box 6)
    - "Pomona's Club", undated (Box 6)
    - "The Squirrel Inn," a play, contract, 1906 (Box 6)
    - "The Boy, the Gun, and the Camera," original manuscript, undated (Box 6)
    - "The Compensated Hosts," original manuscript, a play, undated (Box 6)
    - "Doubtful Blessing," original manuscript, undated (Box 6)
    - "The Early Women of New Jersey," original manuscript, undated (Box 6)
    - "Esop Redivivus," original manuscript, undated (Box 6)
    - Forensic and Literary Circle correspondence, 1855 (Box 6)
    - "The Girl at Cobhurst," contracts, 1898 (Box 6)
    - "The Girl at Cobhurst," correspondence, 1898 (Box 6)
    - "The Story of Viteau," contract, 1884 (Box 6)
    - "The Guardian Angel," original manuscript, undated (Box 6)
    - Letters, 1936, 1954; 2 (Box 6)
    - Extracts relating to Frank R. Stockton Inserted by Marian E. Stockton, Volume VII (Box 7)
    - Notices relating to FRS, selected by Marian E. Stockton, Volume VIII, undated (Box 7)
    - Scrapbook filled with Stockton related articles, undated (Box 7)
    - Extracts relating to FRS, collected by Marian E Stockton, Volume IV, undated (Box 7)
    - "Stocktoniana," lists, letters, and other materials, undated; 2 (Box 7)
    - Notebook about Pforzheimers research on Stockton, undated (Box 7)
    - Letters on politics, 1893 (Box 7)
    - Letter to Emily D. Stockton (niece), 1896 (Box 7)
    - Dr. Evans and the Civil War, MFT Evans to Mrs. Frank Stockton, 1861; 2 (Box 7)
    - Letters J. G. Holland, 1865-1879 (Box 7)
    - Letter: Bronson Howard to Henry Rood, 1899 (Box 7)
    - Letter: Julia Ward Howe to Henry Rood, 1905 (Box 7)
    - Letter: William Dean Howells, 1907 (Box 7)
    - Letter: William Dean Howells to John Kendrick Bangs, 1899 (Box 7)
    - Letter: Lawrence Hutton to Richard Watson Gilder, 1901 (Box 7)
    - Letter: Thomas S. Janvier, undated (Box 7)
    - Letters: Thomas A. Janvier to Henry Rood, 1902 (Box 7)
    - Letters regarding "The Christmas Shadrock," FRS to Gilder, 1891 (Box 7)
    - Letters regarding "The Casting Away," FRS to Gilder, Gilder to Smith, 1886-1900 (Box 7)
    - "The Casting Away of Mrs. Lecks & Mrs. Aleshire," contracts, 1886 (Box 7)
    - Letters regarding "Blackgum ag'in' Thunder", 1901 (Box 7)
    - Letters: to Louise Stockton, 1880-1899 (Box 7)
    - Letter: to John Stockton, 1860 (Box 7)
    - Diary of John D. Stockton, 1866-1867 (Box 7)
    - Letter: Margaret Deland, 1905 (Box 7)
    - Letters: Margaret Deland to Henry Rood, undated (Box 7)
    - Letters: Mary Mapes Dodge, 1874-1893 (Box 7)
    - Mary Mapes Dodge to Louisa May Alcott, 1883-1886 (Box 7)
    - Letters: "The Vizier of the Two-Horned Alexander", 1898-1899 (Box 8)
    - Mary Mapes Dodge to Rossiter Johnson, 1881 (Box 8)
    - Mary Mapes Dodge to Van Noppen, undated (Box 8)
    - Norman Duncan to R. W. Gilder, undated (Box 8)
    - Charles W. Eliot to Henry Rood, 1910 (Box 8)
    - Annie Fields to R. U. Johnson, undated (Box 8)
    - Paul Leicester Ford to Henry Rood, 1901 (Box 8)
    - Charles Dana Gibson, 1937 (Box 8)
    - Letters: Richard Watson Gilder, 1880-1902 (Box 8)
    - Richard Watson Gilder to Henry Rood, 1900 (Box 8)
    - Letter: Horace Greeley, 1856 (Box 8)
    - Letter: Gail Hamilton, 1867 (Box 8)
    - Oliver Herford, 1935 (Box 8)
    - Vassar Female College engravings, 1865 (Box 8)
    - Unidentified engravings, undated (Box 8)
    - Lawrence of Arabia, memorial service program, 1936 (Box 8)
    - Letters: Benson Lossing, 1853-1890 (Box 8)
    - Thomas R. Lounsburg, "In the Defense of Washington," Yale Review, undated (Box 8)
    - Letter: Brander Matthews, 1893 (Box 8)
    - Letter: Thomas Nelson Page, 1892 (Box 8)
    - Joseph Pennell to Richard Watson Gilder, 1886-1891 (Box 8)
    - Letter: Whitelaw Reid, 1862-1863 (Box 8)
    - Letters: Amelie Rives (Princess Troubetzkoy), 1882-1927 (Box 8)
    - Letters: G. W. Cable, 1885-1917 (Box 8)
    - G. W. Cable to the Century, 1886-1910 (Box 8)
    - Harriet P. Spofford to Henry Rood, 1907 (Box 8)
    - Letters: Edmund Clarence Stedman, 1873-1879 (Box 8)
    - Edmund Clarence Stedman to Henry Rood, 1906 (Box 8)
    - Letter: Richard Henry Stoddard, 1893 (Box 8)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 8)
    - Booker, Y. E., 1936 (Box 8)
    - Extracts relating to FRS, collected by Marian E. Stockton, Volume II, undated (Box 9)
    - Extracts relating to FRS, collected by Marian E. Stockton, Volume III, undated (Box 9)
    - Extracts relating to FRS, collected by Marian E. Stockton, Volume V, undated (Box 9)
    - Extracts relating to FRS, collected by Marian E. Stockton, Volume VI, undated (Box 9)
    - "Stocktoniana," volume number unidentified, undated (Box 9)
    - Early writings by FRS, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 9)
    - Diary, FRS, 1902 (Box 9)
    - "The Late Mrs. Null," original play script, Acts I & II, undated (Box 10)
    - "The Late Mrs. Null," original play script, Acts III & IV, undated (Box 10)
    - Bret Harte, "Two Lost Ballads of San Francisco", undated (Box 10)
    - "The Lady or the Tiger?" operetta, contract, 1887 (Box 10)
    - "The Lady or the Tiger?" text of songs operetta, undated (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding "The Lady or the Tiger?" operetta, 1886-1935 (Box 10)
    - "The Lady or the Tiger? and Other Stories," contract, 1884 (Box 10)
    - "The Late Mrs. Null," contracts, 1886 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding "The Late Mrs. Null", 1886 (Box 10)
    - "The Clocks of Rodaine," contracts, 1892 (Box 10)
    - American Antiquarian Society, 1935 (Box 10)
    - "The Christmas Wreck," contract, 1886 (Box 10)
    - Letter regarding "The Adventures of Captain Horn", 1895 (Box 10)
    - "The Adventures of Captain Horn," contract, 1895 (Box 10)
    - Henry E. Huntington Library, 1934-1935 (Box 10)
    - Letters: Mrs. Frank Stockton to Louise Stockton, 1900 (Box 10)
    - "The Lady or the Tiger?" photostat of last paragraph in FRS autograph manuscript, undated (Box 10)
    - "A Field and Afloat," contract, 1900 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding Monticello, 1885 (Box 10)
    - Letters: FRS to Ernest Dressel North, 1890-1899 (Box 10)
    - "The Great Stone of Sardis," correspondence, 1896-1897 (Box 10)
    - "The Great Stone of Sardis," contract, 1896 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding "Pomona and Jona Tell a Story", 1900-1935 (Box 10)
    - Letters regarding "A Slight Mistake", 1894 (Box 10)
    - Letter: FRS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, 1902 (Box 10)
    - Letters: FRS, regarding William Smith Stockton, 1901 (Box 10)
    - Letter: FRS to his mother, Mrs. William S. Stockton, 1880 (Box 10)